<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Rant on Anaminus.Blog</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/blog/tags/rant/</link><description>Recent content in Rant on Anaminus.Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://anaminus.github.io/blog/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How the Plugin Marketplace actually works</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/blog/posts/plugin-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/blog/posts/plugin-marketplace/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id="part-i---the-plugin-compensation-model">Part I - The Plugin Compensation Model&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You are &lt;strong>developing a game&lt;/strong> on Roblox. Some aspect of your workflow is
lacking, so you write a Studio plugin. This plugin improves the workflow of the
&lt;strong>development of your game&lt;/strong>. You rejoice, as you are able to &lt;strong>develop your
game&lt;/strong> better. The hours put into the development of the plugin are compensated
by the increase in revenue deriving from the plugin allowing you to push out
updates and fixes to your game faster and more efficiently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Compensation for hours worked are derived from &lt;strong>your game&lt;/strong>, so putting in work
that doesn&amp;rsquo;t improve &lt;strong>your game&lt;/strong> is wasted work. If you are improving a plugin
that does not result in an improvement to your game, then &lt;strong>you will not be
compensated for your work&lt;/strong>. Thus, if there is no game, but you are still doing
work on plugins, then you are not being compensated.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="part-ii---arent-developers-just-peachy">Part II - Aren&amp;rsquo;t developers just peachy?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Out of the goodness of your heart, you release this plugin for use by other
developers. You have no obligation to do this, nor are you beholden to any other
users of your plugin. You&amp;rsquo;ve already been compensated (by your game), so this is
entirely a charitable gesture. If you&amp;rsquo;re smart, you either maintain it as a
hobby, or just let it sit there while you do more important things.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="part-iii---here-comes-the-money">Part III - Here comes the money&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://devforum.roblox.com/t/400582">Roblox decides&lt;/a> to implement the option to put plugins on sale.
They do this either because they mistake how the Plugin Compensation Model
works, or they think developers&amp;rsquo; charity should be rewarded with some petty
cash.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regardless, this attracts developers to do work purely on plugins. As we know,
because they have no game backing their work, they are compensated only with
enough to buy a nice virtual hat or something. That is, no money.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusions---this-isnt-a-part">Conclusions - This isn&amp;rsquo;t a part&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To summarize, without a game backing your plugin:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Make plugin -&amp;gt; ??? -&amp;gt; No money&lt;/code>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>With a game:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Make plugin -&amp;gt; Improve game -&amp;gt; Yes money&lt;/code>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is how the Plugin Compensation Model has worked since the inception of
plugins, and this is how it continues to work to this day, despite what everyone
thinks, and despite Roblox&amp;rsquo;s apparent efforts to make it look like plugins can
bring in yes money independently. Don&amp;rsquo;t be fooled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Assuming that this model does not change:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The &amp;ldquo;marketplace&amp;rdquo; should be abolished. That is, all plugins should be free.
Allowing a price to be put on plugins tricks developers into believing that
they are a possible source of yes money.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you&amp;rsquo;re a plugin developer, make games instead. Make UGC. Make something
that can be serviced by plugins. Or, secure patrons. Seek contracting or
employment by one of the many studios sprouting up. Make plugins directly in
service of &lt;em>their&lt;/em> content while making them pay you definite yes money.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whatever it is you &lt;span title="oh baby a triple">&lt;em>do&lt;/em> do, do&lt;/span> not
expect compensation for work done on a plugin that isn&amp;rsquo;t directly in service
of a game or other UGC. At best, expect no money.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content:encoded></item><item><title>Stop linking to issues/new</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/blog/posts/new-issues/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/blog/posts/new-issues/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p>You have a neat software project. This project has a presence on GitHub. Maybe
you host the source code there, maybe you&amp;rsquo;re just leveraging the issue tracker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your project also has a website. You know that your users will have problems
with your software, so you want to direct them from your website to your issue
tracker. You want them to have the most streamlined experience possible, so you
get the bright idea of linking to &lt;a>issues/new&lt;/a>. How convenient! One click,
and they&amp;rsquo;re able to start writing a report immediately! Except, that isn&amp;rsquo;t what
happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="login.png" alt="An unsolicited GitHub login page.">
&lt;figcaption>
What actually happens when users click on your link.
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Ugh. Don&amp;rsquo;t assume my intentions. All you had to do was link to the issue page.
It&amp;rsquo;s not like opening a new issue from there is hard.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="new-issue.png" alt="New-issue button on GitHub's issue tracker page.">
&lt;figcaption>
Can't miss it.
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Other reasons why you may not want to do this:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Non-GitHub users are stonewalled from even viewing your tracker without
backtracking to find an alternate route.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A user wants to check for an existing issue before submitting their own. Have
you been noticing a lot of duplicates?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you &lt;em>are&lt;/em> going to pull this stunt, maybe you could at least link to the
issue tracker at the same time?&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Have a problem with this blog? &lt;a
href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Jne9t8sHpUc">Submit a new issue&lt;/a>, or &lt;a
href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dQw4w9WgXcQ">view all of them&lt;/a>. See?
That wasn&amp;rsquo;t so hard.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>